<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ethan Jaffee</title>
    <description>A blog about Ethan Jaffee</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 08:39:42 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 08:39:42 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Goodbye UMass!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What an amazing 6 weeks at UMass Amherst. Not only did I learn about conducting research and get the idea of what living on a college campus is like, I was also surrounded by some of the smartest and creative high school students from all over the globe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished my paper, and I will soon be submitting it for which will be my first (hopefully) publication ever! I would not have been able to accomplish this without the help of the Infant Cognition Lab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the second to last day of the program we held a poster session where all of my peers and I presented our work to each other, family and friends, and UMass faculty. It was amazing walking around knowing how much growth and inspiration had occurred with all of the people around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we all move on to greater things, I know that this is not goodbye, this is see you later. Whether it be a university, office, hospital, etc., this program brought together the future leaders of industries to the faces of medicine, but most of all, the group of students that will change the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next journey will be section leader as band starts next week! Check back to hear more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;font size=&quot;7&quot; color=&quot;Blue&quot;&gt;-Ethan


&lt;/font&gt;
</description>
        <link>/its-all-over.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/its-all-over.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Research</category>
        
        <category>Summer-Programs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Weeks of Research Down!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to believe that I have been here at UMass for four weeks and that summer will be over before I know it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have made a bunch of great friends who are extremely intelligent, pushing me to my full potential, and also showing me where the future of research is headed. It is amazing being immersed in a community where everyone is spending their spare time trying to learn about new things, and actually interested in what everyone has to say. Outside the lab we have done things like hiking or taking a bus to the nice town nearby. Coming to a program knowing nobody was an interesting experience as it was hard to find my place at first. However, it brought experiences that will be helpful for the rest of my life. For example, networking for a job will require interacting with strangers, and I am one step ahead!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also learned a numerous amount of things inside the lab which I would never have learned otherwise. From creating a graph on Excel or dissecting a sheep brain, I have learned more that what I expected to. Whether my paper gets published or not, I have learned what it means to be a researcher. I learned how to collect and analyze data, recruit participants, thoroughly read a scientific article, and so much more. In a normal science class at school we may do a lab which involves testing a hypothesis and following the scientific method. However, I have been doing that every single day, and we are not doing an experiment that is just for learning purposes and we already know what to expect like we do in school.  This is real research where we do not know what we will find. Furthermore, when many think of research they think of chemicals and lab coats, but psychology research is different, and that is why I like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, this summer has been an incredible experience, and I am excited to see what this last two weeks has in store! I will be posting soon about what my specific study is about, so be sure to check back!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;font size=&quot;7&quot; color=&quot;Blue&quot;&gt;-Ethan


&lt;/font&gt;
</description>
        <link>/4-weeks-of-research-down.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/4-weeks-of-research-down.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Research</category>
        
        <category>Summer-Programs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First Two Weeks of Research!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The past two weeks of research have been amazing, I never have learned so much, and never thought I would know so much about babies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lab does a bunch of different studies, but the one I am doing is what we call Language and Social Evaluation. Grown humans within milliseconds label someone as sketchy, scary, trustworthy, etc., and we do it subconsciously. If someone who looked nice and then did something mean like push you to the ground, you would be surprised. We are testing the same with infants. I won’t be going into specifics now, but I will be sure to share my work with you at the end of the summer, but right now I am not permitted to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming into the lab I expected to be treated as a high school student like I am. However, unlike some of the other labs in the program I am treated like a normal lab member. On the daily I am making phone calls, coding, and basically doing anything that is asked of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of the lab, the UMass Amherst campus is absolutely amazing. The sunsets are gorgeous, the people are great, and I am truly getting a sense of what it is like to be a college student.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that is truly amazing about this program is that I am meeting people from all over the country. Everyone here is unique in their own academic and social lives. Being immersed in a group of teens who are extremely intelligent is truly amazing, and I learn something new everyday just by having daily conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I am not in Israel like I thought I might be as mentioned in a previous post, I am still having a once in a lifetime experience here at UMass, and I will never forget it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be sure to check back for more information about my research and other awesome things about this summer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;font size=&quot;7&quot; color=&quot;Blue&quot;&gt;-Ethan



&lt;/font&gt;
</description>
        <link>/First-Two-Weeks-of-Research.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/First-Two-Weeks-of-Research.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>UMass</category>
        
        <category>Research</category>
        
        <category>Summer</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hackathon!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I mentioned in my first post about what a hackathon is, and how it got me into coding in the first place. Basically a hackathon is an overnight event where students code a game, app, website, etc. Different companies from the field come and students can network. These events are normally at colleges, but high school events are getting more and more popular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting this event to happen was much harder than I thought. I thought that the administration would love the idea and want it at our school as soon as possible. This would put our schools STEM department on the map, help us keep up with other high schools in the area already having these events, and overall giving a great experience to high school students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I grabbed some friends together, and we set up a meeting with the at the time Acting Principal. He turned us down, mostly because he was uncomfortable with having students from other high schools that he does not know overnight at our high school. This is a somewhat understandable concern, but there were many solutions to this problem. Major League Hacking (MLH) is an organization that oversees all of these events and has onsite staff the day of the event just incase something goes wrong. However, this was not good enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not stop there. I knew how much this could do for our students, and scheduled a meeting with the Superintendent. I felt that since the Principal was “acting” and new to the job that it would make sense for him to be uncomfortable having an event like this. That is why I went to the Superintendent, who could possibly relieve some of his worries. However, they were not a fan either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next step was inviting all of the administration that was involved to come to a hackathon at a high school nearby. The principal came, and he finally understood what this event was doing for students. Still uncomfortable with the overnight event, he decided he would be okay with a 12 hour event. Even though this was not out original goal, we will make this event an extreme success, and allow our hackathon to grow and hopefully one day be a 24 hour event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This taught me an extremely important lesson, to be persistent when passionate about something. If I took no for an answer, I would not be able to have the opportunity to give such a great academic experience to students. Overall, I will carry this lesson on and not be afraid to stand up, whether it is to an authority figure or not, when I find something I am passionate about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will definitely be posting about the hackathon writing process so make sure to check back!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;font size=&quot;7&quot; color=&quot;Blue&quot;&gt;-Ethan


&lt;/font&gt;
</description>
        <link>/hackathon.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/hackathon.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>hackathon</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Section Leader!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My freshman year in high school I had found a great community of people within the band. It made my transition to a new school so much easier, and it still is giving me an extremely rewarding experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my first year, all of the seniors and the drum majors or section leaders worked super hard to make my time at band as best as it could, and brought extreme success to us all as we won the national championship that year. I learned so much that season, growing as a musician and as an individual while also making a bunch of new friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flash forward two years and I am running for section leader and drum major. This required a lot of time and effort. Written applications, interviews, teaching and conducting auditions, etc. I wanted to give back to the community that gave me so much for two years, and I worked super hard so I could do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, my hard work payed off and I got section leader! As time went on I got more and more excited. I will be carrying on the legacy of the amazing leaders that came before me, carrying on traditions from the past, and giving all of the band members the greatest experience possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not think I truly understand what it means to be section leader yet, but as the season starts and the responsibilities add up I definitely will!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be sure to check back as I will definitely be writing about my new experience as section leader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;font size=&quot;7&quot; color=&quot;Blue&quot;&gt;-Ethan





&lt;/font&gt;
</description>
        <link>/section-leader.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/section-leader.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>band</category>
        
        <category>leadership</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Summer Programs!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have spent a lot of time trying to decide how to have the most worthwhile summer. I had two ideas. After being truly immersed in my Jewish community last summer I thought about going to Israel. I also considered being immersed in an academic environment like taking college courses or doing research on a college campus. I decided I would apply to some programs, and if I got in I would go, and if I got rejected I would go to israel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was looking for research programs in the field of biology or chemistry, but then I found a program that provided psychology research at the University of Massachusetts in Amherst. Normally, when you think about research you think of syringes, lab coats, etc. I had never thought of doing psychology research before, but I applied and I got accepted. The research I will be doing is called Infant Cognition. This is how infants, even at preverbal stages can make decisions and can navigate the world around them. I will be sure to write about the research that I will be doing over the summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I did not get to go to Israel, I still have a great opportunity in front of me. I will learn as much as I can, and get to feel what it is like to live on a college campus. Also, I will definitely be able to travel to israel later in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I am looking forward to letting you know about my summer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;font size=&quot;7&quot; color=&quot;Blue&quot;&gt;-Ethan











&lt;/font&gt;
</description>
        <link>/summer-programs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/summer-programs.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>UMass</category>
        
        <category>Summer-Programs</category>
        
        <category>Research</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Babysitting Children With Special Needs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have worked in the Madrichim program, which is where teenagers can be assistant teachers in classrooms at religious school at my temple for a few years now, and a couple of years ago they were advertising a class about how to babysit children with special needs at the Jewish Community Center (JCC) nearby. It was an amazing experience, I learned a lot about Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD), and most of all I learned how to be more inclusive. After the class was over I was put on their list of people certified to babysit people with special needs, for parents to give a call when they needed an experienced person to watch their kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had never expected to receive a call but one day I did. I babysat for a child with ADHD where I learned a lot, but recently started to babysit a child on the Autism Spectrum where I am learning even more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simultaneously, we were writing our Sophomore Research Paper which also had the theme of ASD. My angle was the portrayal in the media. I learned how often autism is portrayed offensively, incorrectly, and how it has such a large effect on the people’s view of the disorder. Not only are these movies and TV shows being discriminatory, they are also giving false information to the public. It is extremely important for people to understand autism, and advocate for it. I emphasized that joining a walk is great, but if you really want to contribute then help others get informed. Host a session where people who understand the disorder can speak so more and more people can accept the community of people who have this disorder. Therefore, get informed and understand before you believe all of the things you see on TV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a part of the Madrichim Program called Mayan which I will be joining next year. This is an inclusive learning style for people with special needs, and I am more than excited to be a part of this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am looking forward to writing more about my experiences with autism, so be sure to check back for more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;font size=&quot;7&quot; color=&quot;Blue&quot;&gt;-Ethan
&lt;/font&gt;
</description>
        <link>/babyiting-children-with-special-needs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/babyiting-children-with-special-needs.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>babysitting</category>
        
        <category>autism</category>
        
        <category>special-needs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Summer 2016!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last summer I attended a summer program for jewish teens called Urban Mitzvah Corps. Previously I had been going to the same day camp for 8 years, but I decided to something new and I never looked back. During the day we would do volunteer work, but we also did different programs, went on day-trips on the weekends, and overall it was a great experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I copied the blog that I wrote during the program last summer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; The first time I stepped out of my comfort zone was when I learned how to ride my bike. For the longest time, I was terrified of the possible pain and failure that came with trying something new. Even though it was quite possible that I could fall and injure myself, I felt this was a skill that I needed at that age, so I decided to hop on my bike. It was then that my dad gave me a push that set me on the path to a magical moment outside of my comfort zone. 
Here at Urban Mitzvah Corps in New Jersey, we are required to do things we are uncomfortable with everyday. Whether it be doing laundry for the first time, talking to someone that you have just met, or volunteering at a place that is alien to you. At UMC, there are tons of opportunities for participants to step out of their comfort zone, and sometimes, all you need is that push to set you on the path to an extraordinary experience.
From my first day here, everyone has been extremely welcoming and enthusiastic; I knew right away that my summer was going to be unforgettable. The other participants come from all over the country and practice Judaism in their own diverse ways, which gives me the opportunity to learn from every single person in the program. From learning a new song to participating in a tradition that someone else has shared with the group, I am continually stepping out of my comfort zone, which allows me to be educated in all the wonders of Reform Judaism. 
Everyone’s willingness to try new things has made it easier for me to do the same. For example, I tried meditation for the first time this summer. There are very few times in my life when I am able to sit down in the grass, and do nothing but relax and take in all of the things around me. UMC gives us a break from the frustrations that can come with school work, family, and being a teenager. Being here with a group of amazing individuals is a great way to cope with these stresses that can seem unbearable at times.  
Over the past two weeks, I volunteered at a nursing home called Regency Jewish Heritage. This was a turning point in my life because it was the first time that I felt that I was making a difference in other people’s lives. Originally, I was nervous to choose this location because I had very little experience working with the elderly; I was afraid of the situations I could potentially be put in. However, I decided to step out of my comfort zone and see where the experience would take me. 
One unforgettable moment that I had at Regency was when we brought a group of residents to the beach. This was an enlightening adventure not only for us participants, but for the residents as well. As I walked up and down the boardwalk with one lady that was over one hundred years old, she told me how she had not been outside in years, yet alone to the beach. She continued to talk to me about how she used to go to the beach with her husband and her children, which brought obvious joy to her. Watching the residents’ faces light up as they looked out at the beach, breathing in the fresh air, was an extremely heartwarming experience. 
For the rest of my time at Regency, I would check in on this resident daily. Every single day, I would ask her how she was doing and every day she would tell me that she could see, hear, and breathe and that that’s all that mattered, because many others can not. This taught me that I should take advantage of the things that I have. I have the ability to breathe on my own, see, and hear, which is something I shouldn’t take for granted.
Overall, Urban Mitzvah Corps has given me the opportunity to step out of my comfort zone and try new things. Even though this was scary for me at first, all I needed was a simple push from my peers and the staff here in New Brunswick. I would not be having this unforgettable summer without all of them; I have learned that in order to let magic moments happen, I need to get comfortable with being uncomfortable. &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Ultimately this program was a life changing experience, it made me realize how important it is for me to act on all of the problems in our world, it made me more involved in my Jewish life, and most of all I made friends that will last a lifetime and I cannot imagine my life today if I had not met them. &lt;/p&gt; 


&lt;font size=&quot;7&quot; color=&quot;Blue&quot;&gt;-Ethan
 
&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <link>/Summer-2016.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/Summer-2016.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>summer</category>
        
        <category>judaism</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My First Blog Post!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;About a year ago my interest in computer science began after attending my first hackathon, which when putting it simple, is a coding marathon for students. I was not taking computer science in school, and had basically no prior experience, but after the hackathon, with the guidance of my brother who is experienced in the field, I decided to create something of my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to build a blog using a static site generator called Jekyll which would establish a template and a starting point for this blog. However, being a beginner this was much more difficult than I anticipated. I would spend a couple hours accomplishing a simple task that an experienced programmer would be able to do in less than five minutes. I will admit that it was frustrating at times. For example, when there was a bug in the code causing the entire blog to go down in shreds which happened more than once. I probably decided started over 10 times before I finally got it right. However, I am now super excited to have a place to share my academic and social life from a website that I worked hard to create!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will try to post as much as I can and I hope you enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;font size=&quot;7&quot; color=&quot;Blue&quot;&gt;-Ethan

&lt;/font&gt;
</description>
        <link>/first-post.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/first-post.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
        <category>first-post</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
